[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
-This is gonna be rough.
-Yep.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
[PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[ANNOUNCER SPEAKING TAGALOG
OVER PA]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[CELL PHONE DINGS]
-WOMAN ON PHONE: Hi, Dad.
-Hey, Daniela.
I'm rushing to security.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, we're fine.
Just checking in.
-Sorry.
-Are you gonna make it?
Yeah, I think med-checks
should go quickly.
I meant make it here
before midnight.
You're still in Singapore.
Well, Hawaii is 18 hours behind.
It's just over six hours
to Tokyo.
Another six to Honolulu.
So, I'll be there
with plenty of time to spare.
New Year's Eve. One delay...
Hey, hey.
There won't be any delays.
Hold on.
Hey, sorry. I'm running late
this morning.
I just need to scan your badge,
and we'll get you
through quickly.
BRODIE: Thank you.
Now, tell your Aunt Carrie
I'm expecting
some homemade haggis,
neeps, and tatties
waiting for me, all right?
-DANIELA: Okay.
-I'll see you soon.
Hey, Dad.
I'm really glad
that we're doing this.
And I'm sorry
that it's taken so long
for us to be together.
BRODIE Don't apologize.
I know you
have a busy life at school.
Yeah, thanks to you.
That's my job, sweetheart.
I wouldn't have it
any other way.
Well, almost.
[PLANE ENGINE ROARING]
[PANTING]
-MAN: Captain Torrance?
-Yeah, sorry I'm late.
It's fine, sir.
The flight officer
hasn't even come by yet.
-BRODIE: Good.
-Oh. Samuel Dele.
-Nice to meet you.
-Oh, nice to meet you.
-Happy New Year.
-[GRUNTS] And to you.
-Where are you from?
-Uh, Hong Kong, sir.
Did my training at the
Civil Aviation Department.
Oh, yeah.
I hear that's a great academy.
And you, sir?
English, I'm guessing?
Hell, no.
I wouldn't lower myself.
-Nope. I'm Scottish.
-[CHUCKLES] Oh.
Although I did fly
RAF Transport years ago.
Back then,
all the sexy assignments
went to the English blokes.
I didn't mind, though,
because for me,
the heavies were an easy path
into the airlines.
[IPAD BEEPING FAINTLY]
Well, it looks like
they're pushing us
through weather.
BRODIE: Of course they are.
Gentlemen, let's see.
One-hundred and nineteen,
fourteen passengers.
Everything cleared.
Any questions?
Yeah. Looks like
we're pushing through
some serious weather.
It's converging here
over the South China Sea.
We're aware of it.
By the time you get there,
-it should have moved inland.
-What if it sits there
and stews?
We can push out east,
come north over Luzon?
That adds an hour
and 18K in fuel.
The flight's nearly empty,
so we need to shorten.
Take it to 37.
You'll clear that weather.
Good flight. Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Do our iPads
control the weather
like his does?
[LAUGHS]
There you go.
[GRUNTS, SNIFFS]
Hello, gentlemen.
My name's Bonnie.
I'll be your chief tonight.
-Oh. Nice to meet you, Bonnie.
-Good to meet you.
Um, Captain,
you're needed in the Jetway.
-Okay.
-See you soon, Cap.
Captain Torrance,
Flight Commander.
How can I help you?
Fugitive extradition to Toronto.
We'll be with you
as far as Tokyo.
He'll remain in constraints
and be under
my constant supervision.
Well, is he dangerous?
What did he do?
Homicide. 15 years ago.
Wasn't expecting that.
MAN: We found him in Bali
under an alias.
And he's been around,
I'll say that.
Yeah, this is a bare flight.
You're gonna attract
a lot of attention.
I don't wanna scare
the rest of the passengers.
I'm afraid
you're stuck with us, Captain.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
All right.
Just keep away
from everyone else, please.
Copy that.
Let's go.
[PLANE WHOOSHING
IN THE DISTANCE]
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
-Did you check the back there?
-Everything is set back there.
Evening, ladies.
-Evening, Captain.
-Evening. How are you?
-Ah, Isabella, how are you?
-Hey. Good.
-Yeah.
-Good, good.
-Maria. Pleasure.
-Hi, Maria. Yeah.
Brodie Torrance.
We're all ready to get out
of Singapore?
-Yes, sir.
-Okay. Let's go.
Okay.
Okay, confirming 14 passengers.
Fourteen passengers.
New Year's light.
I'm sure everybody's seen
our special guest at the back?
-BONNIE: Louis Gaspare, 35B.
-BRODIE: Mmm-hmm.
What did he do?
I'm sure
the less we know, the better.
You know, just keep
your interactions with him
to a minimum. That's all.
-All right? Good.
-Yep.
So, we're gonna get
this new year started?
-Yes, sir.
-Yes.
All right. Get 'em on board.
Let's have a good flight.
-Okay.
-MARIA: Same to you.
-BRODIE: How you doing?
-BONNIE: Hi, there.
-Happy New Year.
Yeah, just back there.
-Thanks.
-Hi. Happy New Year.
-Hi.
-BRODIE: Hi. Hi.
-Thank you.
-BONNIE: Hi. Happy New Year.
-PASSENGER 3: I'm not gonna
resend it.
-BRODIE: Hi.
-PASSENGER 2: Hi.
-PASSENGER 3:
They've seen his face.
-[WHISPERING] Happy New Year.
They've... They've seen it. I...
-Gary, I can't make them sign.
-BONNIE: Hi, happy New Year.
-BRODIE: Hey.
-PASSENGER 4: Happy New Year.
-BRODIE: Hey, how are you?
-I can't make them sign.
-BRODIE: How're you doing?
-PASSENGER 3: That's your...
BONNIE: Hello. Happy New Year.
-D-F, just right here.
-BRODIE: Hello.
You gotta be kidding me?
How'd you get an upgrade?
Trailmiles.
I've gotta sit
on my own, in coach.
-BRODIE: Happy New Year.
-Happy New Year.
They should tell you
when you buy your ticket
-how old the plane will be.
-No kidding.
Oh, no need to worry, folks.
These planes
are pretty much indestructible.
BONNIE: Hey, girls.
Happy New Year.
-GIRL 1: Hi.
-BRODIE: Hi, hi.
-Hey.
-GIRL 2: Hi.
-I think that's everybody.
-Yeah. Good.
-Okay. All right.
-Okay.
Excuse me, ladies.
That's far enough.
But these are our seats.
I'm in 34D.
It's fine, ladies.
That row there is all yours.
GIRL 1: Okay.
Do you wanna sit by the window?
GIRL 1: Yeah, thanks.
[GIRL 1 SIGHS]
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
[PLANE ENGINE POWERING UP]
[PASSENGERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
-Ma'am, can I help you?
-WOMAN: Oh, thank you.
BONNIE ON PA:
Ladies and gentlemen,
-make sure your seats...
-Excuse me.
-...are in
an upright position...
-Thanks.
...that your seatbelts
are fully fastened
and any carry-on items
you have are fully stowed.
Once again, thank you
for flying Trailblazer.
-Set to max.
-DELE: Takeoff trail.
BRODIE: Trim set for takeoff.
And flight controls.
Flight controls, free and clear.
DELE: Check is complete.
Passengers
all tucked in, Captain.
All right, let's close it up.
Thanks, Bonnie.
[CLOSES DOOR]
[SPEAKER FEEDBACK]
BRODIE ON PA: Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to Trailblazer
flight 119.
This is your captain speaking.
If your next stop is Tokyo,
then you're in the right place.
If you're not going to Tokyo,
then you're about to have
a really long morning.
-[CHUCKLES]
-Flight time this evening
is six hours
and thirty minutes.
And luckily, I know a shortcut,
so we might be there
a little early.
We'll be taking off
just as soon as I learn
a few pages
of this flight manual.
Thank you.
[EQUIPMENT THUDS]
Ready for pushback?
-Ready for pushback.
-Make the call.
-No point to stress about it.
-That's true...
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER
ON RADIO: Trailblazer 119,
you're clear to taxi
Runway Zero-Two Left.
BRODIE: Trailblazer 119,
roger that.
Taxiing Runway Zero-Two Left.
[PLANE ENGINES STARTING]
[FLIGHT ATTENDANT
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[SIGHS] This is one view
that never gets old.
Trailblazer 119 in position,
ready for takeoff.
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER:
Trailblazer 119,
you are cleared for takeoff.
Maintain runway heading,
climb two and maintain 2,000.
BRODIE: Roger that,
and cleared for takeoff.
Fly runway heading.
Climb and maintain 2,000.
Trailblazer 119.
DELE: Takeoff power is set.
Airspeed alive.
[PLANE ACCELERATING]
Eighty. Cross-checks.
90, 100, 110,
120, V-one.
Rotate.
[PLANE ENGINE ROARING]
-Positive rate, landing gear up.
-Landing gear up.
-Flaps up.
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER:
Trailblazer 119, turn right,
heading one-oh-six,
zero degrees.
One-two and maintain
one-zero thousand.
BRODIE: Copy departure.
Trailblazer 119.
[PLANE WHOOSHING]
BRODIE ON PA:
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain speaking.
We've reached
our cruising altitude
of 37,000 feet.
If there's anything you need...
Sir, would you care
for some almonds?
...please don't
hesitate to ask.
We at Trailblazer
appreciate you spending
your New Year's Day with us.
Thank you.
[WHISPERING] Hey, do you want
to take a picture with him?
-What?
-A picture.
Come on.
-GASPARE: Could you not do that?
-GIRL 2: Sorry.
[GIRL 1 CHUCKLES]
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
Beautiful family.
[CHUCKLES] Thank you. Just...
It's a juggle.
But we make it work.
How about you, Cap?
-Do you have a family?
-Yeah, I have a daughter.
Actually, here. Here she is.
Daniela.
I see the resemblance.
[LAUGHS] You think?
-And where's home?
-Daniela goes to college
in California.
And, uh, I'm based
out of Singapore.
The distance must be
quite challenging
for you and your wife, no?
Well, my wife actually passed
three years ago.
-I'm so sorry, Captain.
-No, no.
Thank you. Nah, it's okay.
[SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING]
[PLANE WHOOSHING SOFTLY]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
-Happy New Year.
-Oh, thank you.
ATTENDANT: What can I
get for you, sir?
PASSENGER 3: Uh, gin.
Do you need any tonic
or soda water?
Just gin. Just the gin.
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[DEVICE BEEPING]
We're cutting right through
the top of the storm.
[PLANE RUMBLES]
So much for "moving inland."
[SEATBELT ALERT CHIMES]
[ON PA] Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain speaking.
The seatbelt signs
have been turned on.
Please remain in your seats
with your seatbelts secure.
Thank you.
[EQUIPMENT CHIMES]
Trailblazer 119,
requesting climb
to 40,000 to clear weather.
[STATIC ON RADIO]
TSN control,
this is Trailblazer 119
requesting flight climb
to 40,000 feet
to clear weather. Copy?
[STATIC RADIO]
Comms here are not so good.
TCAS is clear of traffic.
BRODIE: TSN control,
this is Trailblazer 119.
Climbing to 40,000
to clear weather,
in the blind.
-[RADIO FEEDBACK]
-[PLANE ACCELERATING]
[STATIC RADIO]
TSN CONTROL ON RADIO:
Trailblazer 119,
clear to 40,000.
[SCOFFS]
Copy, TSN. Trailblazer 119
level at 40,000.
New Year's crew, huh?
-[PLANE RUMBLING]
-[PASSENGERS EXCLAIMING]
-[ALARM BLARING]
-DELE: Whoa.
[ALARM STOPS]
PASSENGER: What was that?
Okay.
I'm gonna check
on the passengers.
-You have control.
-I have control.
[PASSENGERS WHIMPER, COUGH]
BRODIE:
Nothing to worry about, folks.
Just some weather.
-Here, Bonnie. You okay?
-Oh. Yes.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
-[WOMAN WHIMPERING]
-PASSENGER 3: What was that?
Sorry, folks. Just going
through some weather.
[SIGHS] Is this yours?
-WOMAN: That's mine.
-BRODIE: Oh. Here you go.
WOMAN: Thank you.
He's great with the jokes,
but can he fly the damn plane?
We're doing
the best we can, sir.
Hey, can I at least get a towel?
We'll get you one
just as soon as we can.
What happened? Are you okay?
MARIA: Oh. All good.
Just a scratch.
All right.
Listen, keep everybody
in their seats.
No exceptions. All right?
-[THUNDER RUMBLING]
-[PASSENGERS EXCLAIMING]
[EARS RINGING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
Strap 'em in tight.
BONNIE: Yes, sir.
BRODIE: Bonnie,
stay in your seat.
PASSENGER: What's happening?
[BRODIE EXCLAIMS]
DELE: Captain,
avionics are down.
-[BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
-[THUNDER RUMBLING]
-I have control.
-Copy that.
-Check breakers and reset.
-Resetting.
TSN, this is Trailblazer 119.
Do you copy?
-[SWITCH CLICKS]
-Unresponsive. There's no power.
Avionics must be fried. Shit.
Is anyone on this channel?
Please respond.
Trailblazer 119, flying blind.
Lightning strike.
Avionics down. We are dark.
Does anyone have our position?
[SWITCH CLICKING]
Radio is dead. Resetting.
[RADIO BEEPS, WHIRRING]
[RAIN PATTERING]
System failure.
We're not transmitting.
We're on straight battery.
That gives us 10 minutes
to put her down
before we lose power
and drop
into uncontrolled descent.
[PLANE ROARING]
-Stopwatch.
-[WATCH BEEPS]
DELE: What?
Call it out, Dele.
One minute at a time, okay?
-Okay?
-Okay.
Okay. Manual nav.
Last marked position?
[BRODIE GRUNTS]
427, south southwest of Manila,
heading zero-three-zero.
Given speed and heading,
we should be about here.
[THUDS]
The storm's heading northeast.
We won't make Manila.
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
This is Trailblazer 119.
Descending from 40,000 feet.
No radar, no navigation,
no antenna, no ADI.
Please respond.
Oh, my God.
BRODIE:
Avionics are fried, Bonnie.
It's about to get very rough.
Okay, okay, okay.
[RATTLING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
PASSENGER:
This is not happening.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we've had...
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
Ladies and gentlemen,
we've had
an electrical malfunction
and I need everyone to have
their seatbelts
securely fastened!
We're gonna be forced
to fly through
some severe weather!
-PASSENGER: What happened?
-An electrical malfunction!
I need everyone's seatbelts
to be fully fastened!
BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
Captain.
-Time?
-Eight minutes.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
We're gonna lose the moon.
Keep your eyes on the gyro.
Call it out.
Get ready to take the controls
if anything happens.
[PLANE RUMBLING]
[HAIL SPLATTERING]
That's hail.
Now it's a party.
Shit. We gotta
punch through this storm
and see where we come out.
[BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
[PLANE ROARING]
[SCREAMS]
[WOMAN 1 SCREAMS]
-[YELPING]
-GIRL 1: My phone.
-It's not going through.
-Neither is mine.
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
Come on, baby.
Hold tight. Hold tight.
[WOMAN 2 YELPS]
Oh, my God. Help!
Can you take off the cuffs?
I can't swim.
Not a chance.
[PLANE ROARS]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Go ahead, go ahead.
I got you. I got you.
The goddamn plane
is falling apart!
[GIRL 2 YELPS]
Shit!
[SEATBELT CLICKS]
[GIRL 2 CRYING]
-Sir, you must take your seat.
-Sir? Sir? Sit down.
Stay here. Stay here,
Isabella. Just stay.
-Just stay seated.
-ISABELLA: Sit down!
-Sit down!
-MARIA: Sit down!
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
[PLANE DESCENDING]
-[PASSENGERS EXCLAIMING]
-MARIA: Isabella!
-[BONE CRACKS]
-[SCREAMING]
WOMAN: Oh, my God!
Whoa.
[MAN SOBBING]
Could you help her?
Time?
Five minutes and forty seconds.
[BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
[ENGINE ROARING]
BRODIE: Come on.
Come on, break through.
Oh, fuck.
[PLANE ROARING]
[LOUD WHOOSHING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[RUMBLING STOPS]
There you go.
Time?
DELE: Four minutes
and thirty seconds.
[SOFTLY] Okay.
Can you see land anywhere?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
MARIA: Please, sir, sit down.
Everyone stay
in their seats, please.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[DOOR CREAKS OPENS]
[SOFT RATTLING]
[BONNIE WHISPERING]
Captain, what do I tell
the passengers?
Never thought
I would ever have to say this.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Prepare to ditch.
BONNIE: Okay.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Attention, everyone!
I need you to brace for impact!
The plane is equipped
with flotation devices.
-We're gonna crash.
-BONNIE: And once we are down,
I will give you
further instruction!
-Maria, do you hear me?
-MAN: Where are we landing?
MARIA: Yes, copy that!
Brace for impact!
[SEATBELT CLICKS]
Those white caps
don't look too welcoming.
Time?
Three minutes.
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
[BRODIE SIGHS]
BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
All right, Dele.
Let's give this our best shot.
On my command,
we're gonna turn into the wind
and we're gonna come in
parallel to the swells,
so we touch down slow and level.
Okay?
[BREATHES HEAVILY]
You see that? Over there?
That's fucking land.
[PLANE ROARING]
Feet dry.
Any clue where we are?
We should be somewhere
around here.
[PLANE ACCELERATING]
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Too low terrain.
-[ALARM BEEPING]
-Too low terrain.
That's still working.
[ALARM BEEPING]
-[SWITCH CLICKS]
-[ALARM STOPS]
Captain, 90 seconds.
She'll give us more.
[PLANE ROARING]
[PASSENGERS WHIMPERING]
What's going on?
We can't be landing here.
Twenty seconds.
We might be better off
over the water.
BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
[PANTING]
Out of time.
[GROANS IN FRUSTRATION]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
There!
That's a road. Time?
Ten seconds past zero.
Are you...
That's a fucking road.
[PLANE ROARING]
-Flaps full.
Fuel jettison.
[HISSING]
Visually confirming fuel dump,
my side.
DELE: Nothing here.
Right side failure.
Trying again.
[SWITCH CLICKING]
-Negative.
-Fuck.
We're a stick of dynamite.
Manually extend gear. Hurry.
[WHEELS HUMMING]
Landing gear extended
and locked.
-AUTOMATED VOICE: Low terrain.
-Shut up.
[TIRES SCREECH]
-[WHIMPERS]
-[PLANE WHOOSHING]
No. No.
Speed brakes extended.
Reverse full thrust.
[LOUD RUMBLING]
-Help me with the brakes, Dele.
-On it.
-[WIND HOWLING]
-[GRASS CUTTING]
[WHEELS SCREECHING]
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[ENGINE POWERING DOWN]
Okay.
-[SWITCHES CLICKING]
-Everything off.
[EQUIPMENT POWERING DOWN]
How... How did you...
[PATTING ON BACK]
One minute at a time.
-Right, Dele?
-[LAUGHS]
[SOFTLY] Fuck.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Hell, we still got fuel.
And a hot plane.
Let's get everyone off now.
Let's go.
BRODIE: Dele,
get everybody in the front.
PASSENGER 3: Get me the hell off
this damn plane.
BRODIE: Everybody okay?
Quiet, please.
Everybody, listen up!
I need everybody
off the plane now!
PASSENGER 3:
Which way are we going?
Everybody, quiet.
Go to the front.
I need you all
off this plane now!
[PASSENGERS EXCLAIMING]
MAN: I just wanna know what...
[PASSENGERS CLAMORING]
-Don't worry about your stuff.
-DELE: You need to breathe.
BRODIE:
Get moved to the front.
DELE: Okay, just breathe.
-BRODIE: Bonnie?
-BONNIE: Two!
We have two. Sir, two.
-DELE: Okay, just go.
-Okay, come on. Move, move.
BRODIE:
Let's calmly exit the plane.
Everybody, stay calm.
Let me through.
-Hurry, Bonnie.
-BONNIE: Oh, yes.
In a single line,
come on through. Come on.
BRODIE: Be calm!
Go! Move, move.
[SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING]
BONNIE: Please move to the side.
Please move to the side.
[BIRDS CHITTERING]
[AIR HISSING]
Okay, sit down.
Fold your arms, like this.
Arms crossed, sit down.
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
-Flight 119.
-Uh, I'll call you.
What do we know, Sydney?
SYDNEY: Well, sir,
we lost it somewhere
west of the Philippines.
-Lost?
-The plane requested
a higher altitude
at 5:16 a.m. local.
Nineteen minutes,
23 seconds later,
all communication stopped.
Manila ATC had them on radar
until 5:43 a.m. local
when the plane dipped
below 20,000 feet
and lost all contact.
Get me David Scarsdale,
right now.
BONNIE: Um, we have some cuts
and bruises,
but, um, I think everyone's
just pretty rattled.
BRODIE:
Anyone have cell service?
No. No one.
DELE: What do we do
about the prisoner?
I don't know.
That's a new one
for me.
Um...
I saw him eyeing
the officer's keys,
so I took them.
Is he dangerous?
BRODIE SIGHS]
He's being extradited
on a murder charge.
The officer...
The officer said, yeah,
he might be dangerous.
Look, we just keep an eye on him
and keep him separate
from the other passengers, okay?
Just try your best.
-BONNIE: Okay.
-All right.
BONNIE: Here. I think
you should hold on to these.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
-BRODIE: Okay. Let's go.
-Okay.
BRODIE: Yeah, okay.
WOMAN: Water... Just nowhere.
-PASSENGER 3: What's going on?
-PASSENGER 4: Tell us something.
PASSENGER 5: Yeah.
We need information.
Can we please
get some real answers?
-There's gotta be some thing...
-BRODIE: Okay, everybody...
Everybody... Listen, listen up.
I want to thank you all
for your cooperation.
I'm sorry for what
we just had to go through,
and I know
you all have questions.
-PASSENGER 4: Yeah.
-Yeah.
So, here's the situation.
We got hit by lightning
and our main power
and comms are down.
Okay, so, as of now,
there's no way
of calling for help.
-PASSENGER 3: What?
You're kidding.
-No way? No way?
What I need everybody
to do right now, listen up...
-MAN: How come?
-...is remain calm.
All right? Once the plane
cools down,
we're gonna get back on there,
we're gonna get our things,
get some water
and we're gonna figure out
what we're gonna do.
Do you know where we are?
BRODIE: Yeah, we think
that we're near Davao
in the southern Philippines.
-You think?
-BRODIE: We think.
-PASSENGER 3: Very reassuring.
-BRODIE: Rest assured,
me and the crew are gonna do
everything we can to make sure
that we get you
out of here safely.
All right? Okay. Thank you.
Okay, come on.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
-SCARSDALE: Hey, Terry.
-TERRY: Hey.
Everyone,
this is David Scarsdale.
He specializes
in corporate strategy
and crisis management.
-Happy New Year.
-SCARSDALE: Let's hope so.
Is this
the last point of contact?
Yes, it is.
SCARSDALE:
That's a hell of a storm.
What idiot sent them
flying through that?
It's airline protocol.
Flight was light.
It was the most
efficient route.
I thought
they could fly above it.
You thought? What, are you
a fucking meteorologist, too?
How much fuel did you save?
About $12,000.
Well, congratulations.
That's barely tip money
on this deal.
The clock is ticking.
Every minute matters.
If that plane ditched at sea,
or crash landed,
we can count those minutes
in lives lost or saved. Got it?
Okay, so, what can I do?
Call the military? US assets?
What are your best options?
Well, in that part of the world,
there's only one option
right now.
What's that?
You're gonna want
the lawyers out of here.
TERRY: It's fine. Tell me.
Private assets.
I'm already into it.
-TERRY: Mercenaries?
-Terry...
The Philippines
are not the Amalfi Coast.
Now, I need a group working
on press releases
for every possible scenario.
A ghosting like Malaysia 370.
A crash landing
with no survivors.
A hijacking with demands.
If you have plans
for New Year's Eve,
I just canceled them.
BRODIE: A little further.
Yeah, right to the end.
-Tight as we can.
-MAN: Yeah.
Why can't we just stay inside
the plane?
-[BRODIE SIGHS]
-It's safe and dry.
Well, that's a good question,
Mister, uh...
Sinclair. Matt Sinclair.
Well, without air conditioning,
that plane
is gonna cook in the sun.
So, we're better off out here,
with the shelter and a breeze.
Hey, while you're there,
you wanna step in,
help secure that, Matt Sinclair?
Okay, if you're in your bags,
you find anything like,
uh, bug spray, sunscreen,
food, please share. All right?
Mr. Gaspare.
[SIGHS]
Well...
Looks like we've got ourselves
in a bit of a mess here.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
And so,
I'm not quite sure
what we're supposed
to do with you.
To be honest,
I'm a bit surprised
you're still here.
You think I'm fucking
stupid enough
to try and escape
in a jungle I don't know?
In handcuffs?
Unless you're offering.
I don't think I can do that.
Then we have
nothing to talk about.
[BIRDS CHITTERING]
BRODIE: Shit.
[SIGHS] This is what happens
when a 40-amp fuse
gets hit with enough juice
to light a city.
Check it out, man.
[BRODIE PANTING]
DELE: What about the radio?
[SIGHS]
Let's see here. [SNIFFS] Oh, no.
It's fried, melted.
And the transponder?
[GRUNTS]
It's hard to tell
without the power.
[BRODIE GRUNTS WEARILY]
If we could reroute
the isolation bus
to the essential bus,
we could draw down more amps
from the battery.
In theory.
[EXHALES] Captain,
plane's fully unloaded
except for the, uh,
bodies and their personals.
-I'll handle it.
-BONNIE: Okay.
-Hey, Bonnie.
-Yeah?
Sorry about Isabella.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[UNZIPS BAG]
-What are you doing, man?
-You know what they say.
No video, didn't happen.
Here we all are.
Alone, in the jungle.
No idea of how
we're gonna get out.
Survivors of the worst
fucking plane ride
in the history
of bad plane rides.
There's our lovely plane
that decided
to fall out of the sky.
Trailblazer.
Never flying this again.
There's our snacks.
They're gonna last us
about an hour.
DELE: Zero-sixteen.
Carried that course
for 13 minutes.
So, assuming
the transponder went down
with the lightning strike...
Let's do the math.
That's 17 minutes,
300 miles per hour.
So, multiplying
that out, that's...
Shit.
That's over a thousand
square miles' search radius.
It'll take a miracle
to find us here.
Captain. This island here? Jolo?
It's very, very bad.
-What...
-It's run
by separatists and criminals.
There's no government or police.
If this is where we landed,
we're not safe.
All right, we tell Bonnie.
But let's keep this
to ourselves for now.
MAN: And then there's this guy,
Mr. Mysterious.
Very friendly.
-No, no, no. [GRUNTS]
-BONNIE: Captain!
Keep me out
of your fucking videos!
BONNIE: Hey, did you hit
your head?
Are you okay?
Maria, can you please
get the medic bag?
MARIA: Yep.
I'm gonna need you to do
an on-camera hit
for the press, Terry.
We'll have a statement prepared,
but you'll need
to take questions, too.
Shouldn't we wait till we know
a little bit more?
If we wait until we know more,
it looks like
you're hiding something.
Just show
your concern, be humble.
-You know the drill.
-Got it.
Here you go. [SIGHS]
You, Mr. Fuckin' Weatherman.
Time to redeem yourself.
I need everything
on that aircraft.
Flight times, maintenance logs.
Names of the techs
who last serviced the plane.
-Everything.
-Yes, sir. Got it.
[BAG UNZIPPERING]
[ANIMALS CHITTERING]
[SIGHS]
[BRODIE GRUNTING]
[EXHALES]
You sure about this, Captain?
No.
But we're running pretty low
on options.
Look, I'm not tying him up.
If he runs, at least he's away
from the others, right?
All right.
Let's go and break it
to the others.
[ZIPS BAG]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
All right, everybody. Listen up.
So, here's our situation.
Mr. Dele and I,
from our calculations,
we believe that we have landed
on an island
somewhere in the Sulu cluster.
We don't know which island.
The problem is the area
between where the transponder
was struck by lightning
to here is so vast
that search and rescue
could take some time.
-Jesus Christ.
-MAN: How long is it gonna take?
We're also gonna have to ration
food and water.
What's your next move?
Smoke signals?
Can you just keep it
to yourself?
Cut him a break.
At least he landed the plane.
We didn't crash.
We're in the middle
of nowhere though.
-We're stranded.
-MATT: Yeah, come on, man.
MAN: We didn't crash, man.
BRODIE: Listen, last night,
we flew over
some kind of facility.
I'm hoping they have a phone
or a radio.
If I can get there,
make contact,
we could be rescued in hours.
Until then, I need everybody
to be careful
because we don't know
what's going on in that jungle.
-I'll go with you.
-I will come, too.
I appreciate it.
But Mr. Gaspare
has kindly volunteered to come.
MATT: [SCOFFS] What?
MAN: You're taking a guy
in handcuffs?
-[SCOFFS]
-Makes sense.
[HANDCUFFS CLINKING]
[SIGHS]
Come on.
MAN: Datu!
Datu!
[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
Well, we're doing everything
we possibly can
to find Flight 119,
sparing no expense.
REPORTER: Have you determined
that the plane has crashed?
Uh, no, that's not
the assumption.
-We have very little...
-You sure it's Dad's flight?
-We are coordinating...
-CARRIE: I'm sure.
TERRY: ...the search and rescue
efforts in the region.
No.
TERRY: As soon as we have
some updates,
hopefully some positive news,
we'll get right back to you.
[BIRDS CHITTERING]
I peeked through
your officer's bag for supplies.
I came across your pocketknife.
You former military
or something'?
Groupe des
Commandos Parachutistes.
French Foreign Legion.
Pay and benefits suck,
but they don't ask any questions
if you can hack it.
Questions?
Nothing's black
and white, Captain.
I was just at the wrong place
at the wrong time.
No one cares
what really happened.
I was 18 and fucked.
So, rather than, uh,
rot in prison,
I ran, joined the Legion.
End of story.
BRODIE:
How'd you get caught?
Forget it. Doesn't matter.
[EXHALES]
Now let me ask you something.
Did you bring my knife?
Sorry, no.
I left it in the bag.
How about
the dead officer's gun?
BRODIE: We should
be getting close about now.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SIGHS]
SCARSDALE: Brodie Torrance.
Scottish, UK citizen.
Royal Air Force.
Then flew commercial
for 20 years.
New York to London,
Paris, Tokyo. Hot-shit routes.
Since then,
he's been flying Egypt,
Meridiana, Frontier
and Trailblazer,
flying shit third-tier routes.
-Why? What happened?
-Check the video file.
MAN: Hey, where's my drink?
-Oh, Jesus.
-I asked you for a drink,
like, 10 minutes ago.
What do you want?
Get out of here.
BRODIE: Hey, hey, hey!
-What the hell is going...
-[GRUNTS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[MAN CHOKING]
Can this get any worse?
That's right. That's right.
I like this guy.
[SIGHS]
[DELE GRUNTS]
[SWITCH CLICKING]
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
[CHUCKLES]
Holy shit.
-[BIRDS CHITTERING]
-[INSECTS TRILLING]
[METAL CLINKS]
[WHISPERING] Fuck. Okay.
[WINCES]
SCARSDALE: John Shellback,
it's David Scarsdale.
What's your status?
We're prepping to load now.
Should be in the air 0900.
Please, Scardy, tell me
we're going back to Macau.
[CHUCKLES] File a flight plan
for Manila,
and we'll see
how things shake out.
SHELLBACK: Are you telling me
you have no idea
where this plane actually is?
It's not in Macau.
I can tell you that.
That's gonna be extra, Scardy.
That's going to be extra.
Happy fuckin' New Year.
Out.
They're on their way.
They'll reach the area
in about three hours,
then parachute in
once we get
the plane's location.
JIM: So, how much
in the emergency fund?
Half million.
Great. That might be enough
to get one of us
-out of Indonesian prison.
-Here.
-Are we good, boys?
-Good now. There you go, boss.
[DIAL TONE]
[EXHALES]
One, eight...
[LINE RINGING]
WOMAN: Welcome
to Trailblazer Airlines.
-This is Carmen.
-Carmen, listen carefully.
This is an emergency.
I'm Captain Brodie Torrance.
Trailblazer 119.
We've gone down on an island
in the Sulu Sea.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
My name
is Captain Brodie Torrance.
And I'm the captain
of Trailblazer 119.
Now, we've gone down.
We made a crash landing on...
Sir, we've been
getting crank calls
-all day about this.
-No. Hello?
I hear you. I'm here.
Now, I need you
to patch me through
to emergency ops immediately.
Listen, we've been getting
calls all day about this.
-Just shut up and listen.
-Calm down, sir.
-We've been getting...
-Sorry.
...crank calls all day long
about this disappearance.
Now, can you tell me
your employee badge number.
[WHISPERING] Fuck.
I don't actually have
my badge on me, Carmen.
-I need you
to believe me on this.
-Sir, without your badge...
-Carmen.
-Sir...
-Can you hear what I'm saying?
-I can hear you.
-Our flight has gone down.
-Without your badge number...
-I'm the captain of Trail...
-[LINE DISCONNECTS]
Hello?
[SIGHS]
Nail the badge
to my fucking head.
[DIAL TONE]
All right, Daniela.
Don't let me down.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATING]
-[LINE CRACKLING]
-Hello?
[BRODIE SIGHS] Daniela?
Thank God.
-Hey, can you hear me?
-[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
-Now, listen. Don't...
-Dad? Is that you?
-Yes, sweetheart. It's me.
-You're okay?
-Dad.
-I'm okay, I'm okay.
Now, don't talk. Just listen,
'cause we might cut out, okay?
Quick. Grab something
to write with.
-Dani?
-Not now, Aunt Carrie.
-Is that your dad? Dani.
-Yes, yes!
-Where are you, Brodie?
-Okay, I got it.
We've gone down, all right?
I want you to write what I say,
and get it
to Trailblazer immediately.
DANIELA: Okay.
All right, we're on an island
somewhere in the Jolo cluster
in the Sulu Sea.
Now, we have no radio.
And I don't know
what island we're on.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Wait, no, stop!
-DANIELA: Dad!
-Wait!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[THUDDING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[KNIFE CLATTERS]
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
BRODIE GRUNTS]
[BONE CRACKS]
[NECK CRACKS]
[PANTING]
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GROANS]
Oh, fuck.
[GRUNTING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GUNSHOTS]
[WHISPERS] Fuck.
[DOOR OPENS]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
You can come out, Captain.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Drink it all. Hurry.
We gotta move.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Are you okay?
No.
GASPARE: Would you rather
that be you?
-No.
-That's it, then.
You bury it all.
Deal with shit later.
Reach anyone?
Yes.
But we can't depend on it.
I got cut off.
It's loaded.
Slip the safety and shoot.
[MOTORCYCLE REVVING]
[MAN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
GASPARE: Lucky for you,
I snuck up on these guys.
I got a feeling
we're gonna see a lot more.
[WHISPERING] Hey. Hey.
Come here.
Look.
Hey, they've got passports here.
[BEEPS]
Filipino, UK.
[GASPARE WHISPERING]
Hey, Torrance.
Look here.
[TAPE WHIRRING]
Mark and Maria Burnham.
Missionaries with
the Good Samaritan Fellowship.
Holy shit.
$200,000 needs to be prepared
in cash by tomorrow.
They say instructions
to follow for that
by tomorrow or they're...
They're gonna kill us.
I gotta get to the passengers.
[GROANS]
Ah, shit.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Come on.
[METAL CLANKING]
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
-MATT: Do you hear that?
-Yeah.
Someone's coming.
[INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
-Hey. Hey!
-Hey, hey!
-MAN: Hey!
WOMAN 1: We're here.
Yes! We're here!
DELE: Hey, get back. Get back!
Get back, get back.
We don't know who it is.
-Get back! Get back in!
-WOMAN 2: Come on.
-MAN: Hey, hey!
-DELE: Stop!
-[GUNS FIRING]
-[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Hear that? Stop the truck.
What?
What the fuck
is the matter with...
[GUNS FIRING IN DISTANCE]
-[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
-Oh, shit.
[FIRING CONTINUES]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[BRIE WHIMPERS]
[IN ENGLISH] Where is captain?
I'm in charge.
[WHISPERING] Hey, hey.
MAN: Give list. Passenger list.
Oh, shit. Yeah,
I've gotta go in there.
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
No, wait, wait, wait.
[BONNIE WHIMPERS]
Passenger list.
Captain Brodie Torrance?
Captain Torrance isn't here.
HAJAN: Where is he?
-[PASSENGERS EXCLAIMING]
-Where is he?
Hey, hey, hey, stop. Stop.
He went...
He went looking for help.
-MAN: Help where?
-I don't know!
Just a phone, a radio!
So, no one know you're here?
[BREATH TREMBLING]
-[ROSALIE SCREAMS]
-JOSHUA: No!
[PASSENGERS SCREAMING]
[GASPS, SIGHS]
[SCREAMING]
[JOSHUA SCREAMING]
[MACHETE UNSHEATHES]
[PASSENGERS EXCLAIM]
[GROANING] Oh.
[SOBBING] Oh, my God.
Passport.
[PASSENGERS WHIMPERING]
Get on bus, now!
-[GUN FIRING]
-[PASSENGERS SCREAMING]
Go! Move!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
REBEL: Move!
[WOMAN EXCLAIMS]
No, no, no, no, no.
[MALE FIGHTERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[IN ENGLISH]
Fuck is wrong with you?
What the fuck is your problem?
What the fuck were you gonna do?
It's a fucking army.
[PANTING]
BRODIE: We can still find out
where they are.
They're gonna know
Then what? Oh, God.
-BRODIE: They're gonna know.
-The fuck?
-BRODIE: Hey!
-Fuck. Fuck. Fuck.
[BRODIE GRUNTS]
-[GUNSHOT]
-[BRODIE GRUNTING]
Don't fucking move.
[BOTH PANTING]
-GASPARE: You speak English?
-Yes. Yes.
-Little. Little.
-GASPARE: Empty your pockets.
-Come on.
-Okay.
GASPARE: Hands over your head.
[DATU SPEAKING TAGALOG ON RADIO]
Who's that?
Datu Junmar.
He in charge.
GASPARE: "Datu" means "chief."
BRODIE:
Where's he taking them?
Hey! Where's he taking them?
I tell you, Datu kill me.
-Kill my family.
-Me or Datu?
Dandulit village.
Where is he keeping them
in Dandulit?
Come on. Come on!
Warehouse, on the river.
Then boat takes.
Boat takes 'em where?
I don't know.
Where? Fucking tell me where.
-[GRUNTS]
-[GROANS]
-GASPARE: Tell me. Come on!
-[GROANS] I don't know!
Whatever Datu say, we do.
I gotta go after them.
And do what? We should wait.
You said you made contact.
I don't know
how much got through.
And I'm not waiting here
to find out.
They're my passengers.
They're my responsibility.
You don't have to come.
I'm not expecting you to.
[ON RECORDING]
And I'm the captain
of Trailblazer 119.
Now, we've gone down.
We made a crash landing on...
CARMEN: Sir,
we've been getting crank calls
-all day about this.
-No. Hello?
CARMEN: I hear you. I'm here.
BRODIE: Now, I need you
to patch me through
to emergency ops immediately.
CARMEN: Listen,
we've been getting
calls all day about this.
-Just shut up and listen.
-CARMEN: Calm down, sir.
After that call was cut off,
Torrance phoned his daughter,
Daniela, in Maui.
She confirmed the details
of the recording.
And she said he told her
they went down
somewhere in
the Jolo island cluster.
I need Key Hole satellite access
to this area to find that plane.
Our assets are going airborne,
and we'll circle
the Jolo cluster
until we get them
a drop location.
But I need you
to call in some favors
-and make it happen.
-Got it.
[POWERING UP]
[WHISPERING] Good job, Dele.
[TURNS OFF MACHINE]
[WHISPERING] Passen...
-[GUNSHOT]
-[BIRDS CHITTERING]
[WINGS FLUTTERING]
Dandulit village
is one road in, one road out.
Is this any use to me?
You speak Tagalog?
[GRUNTS]
-[KEY CLICKS]
-[ENGINE STARTS]
Yeah, she's plugging it in now.
Wait, I got... I think...
-We got it. We got it.
-We're there.
Found it. Dave, found the plane.
Jolo island. Torrance was right.
Stand by.
SCARSDALE: And there it is.
TERRY: Can't believe
it's intact.
Sending the coordinates
to our assets now.
They'll drop on-site ASAP.
Well, there's really no need.
They'll contact
the Philippine government.
Surely, they'll send
local authorities
-with a search and rescue.
-It won't be that easy, Terry.
-TERRY: Why?
-Because there is
no authority on Jolo island.
It's run by separatists
and militias.
The Filipino army
won't even go there anymore.
They got their asses kicked
so many times.
Look, the guys
will parachute in.
But they're gonna need some help
getting everyone out.
[ENGINE STOPS]
BRODIE SIGHS]
The village is two kilometers
in that direction.
You know you can't
just ask for them back.
Yeah, well,
you're the military man.
I was hoping
you'd have some ideas.
[CHUCKLES]
Ah, man.
Thank you...
[SIGHS] for helping.
A priest in the Legion
used to say,
"Redemption can only be found
in the most unusual places."
[EXHALES] Well,
this certainly qualifies.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]ING
[LOCK OPENS]
[HAJAN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[DELE SPEAKING IN ENGLISH] Wait.
Hey, hey. Hey, stop!
Stop! What are you doing?
Yeah, hey, stop!
-[GRUNTS]
-[BODY THUDS]
Come. Come on.
Come here. Come on.
[MALE FIGHTER
SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[BRIE CRYING]
-Come, come, come.
-No. No!
[MEN GRUNTING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[GUN CLICKS]
[HAJAN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[IN ENGLISH] Name. Country.
-[THUDS]
-Oh!
Name! Country!
Maxwell Carver, England.
Name. Country.
Brie Taylor, American.
-[GUNSHOT]
-MATT: Oh!
HAJAN: Name! Country!
Matt Sinclair, American!
Name. Country.
Katie Dhar, Sweden.
Samuel Dele, Hong Kong.
[HAJAN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[REBELS SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[SHELLBACK BREATHING HEAVILY]
Shellback. Two dead jundies.
SHELLBACK:
Roger that. Set security.
Go police up the chutes.
Get them out the open.
Trailblazer CP,
this is Shellback 6.
How copy?
We got you on comms, Shellback.
Getting your visual up now.
[SHELLBACK BREATHING HEAVILY]
SHELLBACK:
Let's check the plane.
Check. On you.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATES]
Yeah, Terry here.
What do you mean, "No?"
We've got two bodies
in the rear galley.
Give us a look.
Shit.
Looks like it might be
crew members.
Did you properly convey
the urgency of the situation?
-Zip 'em up. We got 'em.
-That's unacceptable.
That is unacceptable.
You tell 'em I said that.
[TERRY SIGHS]
Filipinos won't send
a rescue team
without a battalion
of troops in support.
They're saying 24 hours.
True to form.
Any sign of the passengers
or the rest of the crew?
SHELLBACK:
That's a negative, boss.
At least from
what I see right now.
Shit.
Trailblazer CP,
you're seeing this, right?
Looks like we may have
a hostage situation
on our hands.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING
IN DISTANCE]
GASPARE: You see the boats?
They're fueling them up.
[WHISPERING] Shit.
Taking them off the island.
Once they're gone, that's it.
[CHICKENS CLUCKING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
We have to do this quietly.
No guns until
we absolutely have to.
That's it? That's your plan?
You got a better one?
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[PANTING] Oh, shit.
[DOG BARKING]
That's him. That's Junmar.
[CONVERSING INDISTINCTLY]
BRODIE: That's the bus.
They gotta be in that house.
This way.
[SHEEP BLEATING]
[DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE]
[ROOSTER CROWING]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[SHEEP BLEATING]
[GRUNTS]
BRODIE: [WHISPERING] Oh, shit.
[KEYS JINGLING]
[WHISPERING] Go.
GASPARE: Psst.
[GRUNTS]
[ALL GASP]
-[THUDS]
-[BARS CLANKING]
[WHISPERING]
Hey, everybody okay?
-MAN: Yes.
-Yes.
-WOMAN: What's happening?
-All right. Okay.
We're gonna get
everybody freed up
and ready to move.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Hey, I'm gonna
have a look around.
BRODIE: Okay.
Now, we're gonna load back up
on that bus.
-MAXWELL: Where are we going?
-Back to the plane.
What?
It's all right.
I've made contact
with Trailblazer.
I'm not sure what got through,
but they know we're alive.
So, they find that plane,
and they find us. All right?
-Everybody ready to move?
-BONNIE: Yes.
All right. Shh.
[WHISPERING] Quiet. Fast.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Okay. Quick, quick, quick.
Quick. Hurry.
Hurry, hurry, hurry. Go, go, go.
Can you drive this thing?
Yeah. I can drive anything.
Okay. Here are the keys.
I think it's the big one.
-[WHISPERING] Stop.
-What?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
There's a bunch
of armed fuckers on the road.
We're gonna get mowed down
if we try to drive past them.
I can engage 'em,
but it's just gonna
draw more of 'em.
Shit.
[BREATH TREMBLING]
Okay, I can handle these guys.
How are you gonna do that?
I'm gonna distract them.
I'm gonna give myself up.
-That's your plan?
-Oh, you have a better one?
Look, we don't have
any other choice.
You're never gonna see
your goddamn family again.
What about their families?
Look, you know
I have to try, right?
I mean, I'm the captain.
These assholes
are never gonna kill me.
Worth too much to them.
-[SIGHS]
-GASPARE: Yeah.
Wait here. Take this.
[EXHALES]
[SHOUTING] Hello? Anyone?
[REBELS SPEAKING TAGALOG]
I need to speak to Junmar.
[REBELS SHOUTING IN TAGALOG]
BRODIE: And I'm unarmed!
No, I'm the captain.
I'm the pilot here.
[REBELS SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[IN ENGLISH] You're a pilot?
Captain Torrance?
I need to speak to Junmar.
Datu Junmar.
Other pilot say
you leave passengers
to call for help.
How that go for you?
[SIGHS]
I came to talk to you
about that.
I contacted Manila.
They send, uh,
search and rescue for us,
lots of soldiers.
So, I'll be having
my passengers back, thank you.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
JUNMAR: You think you come here,
speak to me,
tell me do what you say.
You think backwards.
You in Jolo now, Pilot Torrance.
No rescue coming.
Look, we had problems
in the air.
I had to land the plane.
My people just want to go home.
-You can understand.
-They're my people now.
You're mine.
No matter why.
Everything in Jolo belong to me.
Until I don't want.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
No one care when small man die.
But I make example of big man?
I kill him?
Now they care. Now they pay.
[GROANS]
Fuck you.
Hajan.
[BRODIE GROANING]
[SPEAKS TAGALOG]
[GUN FIRING]
[REBELS SHOUTING]
They're friendlies, Captain.
Stay where you are.
[GUNS FIRING CONTINUES]
You hurt?
Captain Torrance, are you hurt?
No, I'm okay.
SHELLBACK:
We got the package intact.
Eastern row, main house.
How copy? Shellback, out.
-Lake, you got the package.
-No, wait. Take the others.
Hey, we got them. Let's move!
Move!
SHELLBACK: Move! Move in!
Got you. Move.
-Everybody okay?
-Everybody, get down!
Roll out! Roll out now!
[GUN FIRING STOPS]
[DATU PANTING] Hajan!
Hajan.
[WHIMPERS]
[IN TAGALOG]
[BIRD CHIRPING]
Took a hell of a beating,
Captain. How are you feeling?
BRODIE: Okay. Okay, thanks.
Who are you guys?
SHELLBACK: We're Trailblazer's
forward advance crew on this.
John Isaac.
Mo, Willis, and Lake.
So, hold on.
You're the advance crew.
When is the rescue team
getting here?
SHELLBACK: Twenty-four hours
is the best Trailblazer can do,
so, unfortunately,
we just became the rescue team.
Twenty-four hours.
We won't be left by then.
I understand, and that's why
we need to work up
a contingency.
Now, we did bring
an emergency fund,
but not enough to buy our way
off this island. So...
What do you suggest
we do, Captain?
[WHISPERING] Fuck.
[SIGHS] I got a plan.
No, that's not the assumption.
We have very little information
at present.
However, we are coordinating
with all the search
and rescue efforts
in the region.
-Hopefully...
-[TURNSTV OFF]
Dad.
I don't know
if you'll get this, but...
I love you so much.
You are the most
amazing father.
And I'm sorry
if I don't say it enough.
I don't know what's happening.
Or if you're hurt.
I'm so scared.
[DANIELA CRIES]
So, just please come home.
[ON RADIO] Trailblazer CP,
this is Shellback 6.
Let's wait a sec.
Copy, 6. What's your status?
SHELLBACK: Hostages secure,
but we've got another plan.
You're not gonna like it.
BRODIE:
Come on. Everybody, hurry.
BONNIE: Run, run, run!
BRODIE: Hey, gather them here.
-DELE: Everyone, come on.
-BRODIE: Gather around.
Come on!
Now, there is
no full rescue team
coming anytime soon,
not for the next 24 hours.
-MATT: What?
-BRODIE: We can't wait.
They are gonna come at us
with everything they've got,
and we're not gonna survive.
Now, Dele and I managed to get
the power back up on the plane.
SHELLBACK:
...from the west end.
We only have one chance.
And that is me flying us
out of here in this thing.
-Wait, wait, wait. What?
-MAN: No way in hell.
-BRODIE: I know.
-DELE: Listen, listen.
Listen, listen, listen!
If I didn't believe
it could be done,
I would not put you guys
back on that plane.
I have a daughter.
I have every intention
of hugging her again
and making it home.
And I'm telling you
that the way home
is on this plane.
I've got you this far.
I just need you to trust me
this one more bit. Okay?
-All right, preflight checks.
-Copy that.
-Everybody, follow Mr. Dele.
-DELE: Follow me, come on.
-Okay. All right.
-DELE: Come on!
[PASSENGERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Come on!
Shellback, how long have I got?
Two minutes tops.
Can't be certain
the damage already done
won't affect
flight characteristics
or that the engines won't fail.
SCARSDALE: Shellback said
it can be done.
He's the man on the ground.
Short of proper inspection,
he's not qualified
to make that determination.
They're being hunted, Terry.
And you're talking
about inspections?
After all they've been through,
imagine the fallout
if I allow Torrance
to fly that plane
and incinerate everybody in it.
Imagine the fallout
if you don't.
Make sure they get on okay.
Come on.
-Run, run, run!
-[GRUNTING]
[PASSENGERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Everybody on.
BONNIE: Come on. Let's go.
Let's go, Maria.
[GRUNTING]
BRODIE: Ah, fuck.
We're about to have a lot
of bad guys up our asses.
I'm gonna need you
to pick up the pace, Cap.
-BRODIE: All right.
-We've got two convoys
here and here,
and it looks like a third
is not far behind.
All right. I gotta
fix this brake first.
-You gotta buy me some time.
-Got it.
MARIA: Like she said,
let's go. Let's go.
[BRODIE GRUNTING]
[GUNS FIRING]
-[EXCLAIMS]
-[SCREAMS]
-Move!
-Bonnie!
I got it, Captain! Help!
BONNIE: Keep moving.
[GUN FIRES]
Move! I can't get him.
Move, move, move!
Time to go, Captain!
Time to go now!
[GUNS FIRING CONTINUES]
[GROANS]
[CONVERSING IN TAGALOG]
[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[GROANS]
[MAN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
-[GROANS]
-[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
Reloading!
[REBEL SHOUTING IN TAGALOG]
[GROANS]
Moving!
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[GRUNTS]
[MAN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[IN TAGALOG]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[MALE FIGHTERS
SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[BOTH GROANING]
[MEN SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[GROANING]
[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
Shellback! Shellback,
I need comms.
It's already
on the team channel.
Once I start the engines,
you have two minutes.
-I'll leave the stairs down.
-Roger that.
You know I can't get
on that plane with you.
-Right?
-Yeah, okay. Good luck.
-You too, my capitan.
-[CHUCKLES]
[GROANS]
[JUNMAR SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[SHOUTING IN TAGALOG]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[PASSENGERS CLAMORING]
Find a way
to strap him in, Bonnie.
Everybody, stay down, okay?
Just hang with me
just a little bit longer.
The cabin doors won't seal
without a reset.
Keep them open,
all of them, okay?
So they're balanced.
Avionics still shot.
Nothing on screens.
Checked the hydraulics.
They look good.
-Okay. APU working?
-[CHIMES]
-DELE: APU working.
-Engaged?
-Engaged.
-BRODIE: Okay.
All right, Dele.
[PANTING]
Start 'em up.
DELE: Starting engines.
-[SYSTEM WHIRRING]
-BRODIE CLEARS THROAT]
BRODIE GROANS]
-You okay?
-Yeah, I'm okay.
-[GUNS FIRING]
-Get down!
[GUNS FIRING CONTINUES]
Shit. I'm out of ammo.
Check our pallet.
Lake, reloading!
[MALE FIGHTER 1 SCREAMS]
[MALE FIGHTER 2
SPEAKING TAGALOG]
Reloading!
[SHOUTING IN TAGALOG]
[GROANING]
-[GROANS]
-[SHOUTING]
[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
GASPARE: Shit.
[REBEL SPEAKING TAGALOG]
BRODIE: I need you
with me, Dele.
-Keep your focus in here.
-[BEEPS]
Hey, into the live.
Let's turn this baby around.
[ENGINES POWERING UP]
[IN TAGALOG]
They hit our fuel tanks,
we're toast.
[BULLET RICOCHETS]
This is Captain Torrance.
Is anyone there?
Is anyone there, God damn it?
I'm about to take off.
Captain, you listen to me.
That plane stays
right where she is.
-Am I understood?
-Captain Torrance,
my name is David Scarsdale.
Tell me what you need.
BRODIE:
I need directional assistance.
We have no radar, no nav.
We are fully manual.
I figure we've got
about 300 miles tops.
Find me a place to land.
Shellback.
I need you and your men
on the plane now.
I'm gonna go as soon
as we make this turn.
-Get to the plane!
-Check.
Cover me!
Let's go!
[GUNS FIRING CONTINUES]
DELE: Do we have enough road?
It's gonna have to be.
Gaspare, move! Move!
Gaspare, move!
Gaspare!
JIM: Come on!
Let's go!
My wing clear.
-[BULLET RICOCHETS]
-My wing is clear.
Can't wait
any longer, Shellback.
What's your status?
SHELLBACK: Go on.
Take us up, Captain.
[SPEAKING TAGALOG]
[BULLETS RICOCHET]
Get down!
[GROANS]
BRODIE: What the fuck?
[YELLING]
Full throttle.
[PLANE ACCELERATING]
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[PLANE RUMBLING]
BRODIE GRUNTS]
DELE: Cap, your shoulder.
I'm okay.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
We're losing power,
right engine.
-Shutting it down.
-BRODIE: No!
We need all the thrust
we can get.
-We're gonna hit.
We're gonna hit.
-Save left engine.
[WHIMPERS]
Come on.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Lost right engine.
Shut it down now.
Shutting down two.
[ENGINE POWERING DOWN]
How bad?
Right wing's trailing edge
is damaged.
Shit. Okay,
just keep an eye on it.
This is Trailblazer 119.
We're airborne.
TRAILBLAZER CAPTAIN:
Trailblazer 119,
reading your air speed
at 135 knots.
Bordering stall rate.
This is as fast as she'll go.
TRAILBLAZER CAPTAIN: Reading
your altitude at 400 feet.
You need to take her up to 3,000
or she's not staying up.
BRODIE: Negative on speed
and altitude.
119, you need
to take her up now.
We have no fucking doors.
We're depressurized,
we're low on fuel
and we just lost an engine.
Now, don't tell me
what I already know.
Find me a place to land.
WOMAN: Pulling up lists
of available airfields now.
Let's get it up on the screen.
TRAILBLAZER CAPTAIN:
Best option, Siasi Island,
50 miles due south.
Adjust your heading
to 15 degrees.
There's a small airport there.
Can you make it?
[GRUNTS] We're gonna find out.
Jungle cleared. Feet wet.
[PLANE RUMBLING]
Have a visual on Siasi.
Come on. Come on, baby.
Just a little bit more.
Lost right-side control.
Losing altitude.
Have a visual on Siasi runway.
Prepare for landing!
Brace for impact!
[PLANE RUMBLING]
[ENGINE WHIRRING]
[RUMBLING]
BRODIE: Full reverse on one.
Speed brakes.
[ALL EXCLAIMING]
Help me on the brakes, Dele.
[SCREECHING]
BRODIE
BREATHES HEAVILY, GRUNTS]
[PLANE SCREECHES]
[INTENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Oh.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[PANTS]
-[CHUCKLES]
-MAN: Are we okay?
Yes.
BRODIE BREATHING HEAVILY]
[UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING]
[ALL APPLAUDING]
MAN: Good job.
Congratulations, everyone.
Thank you.
[EXHALES, CHUCKLES]
You okay?
[SIGHS]
I've had better days.
[CHUCKLES]
One minute at a time, right?
One minute at a time.
[CHUCKLES]
[SIREN BLARING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[PASSENGERS APPLAUDING]
[MAN WHOOPING]
You're a hell
of a pilot, Captain.
-Mission accomplished?
-SHELLBACK: Absolutely.
You need to see someone?
BRODIE:
Let's keep moving, everybody.
-SHELLBACK: You're the captain!
-KARIM: Come on, man.
-KATIE: Oh! [LAUGHS]
-BRODIE: Yeah.
[RESCUE TEAM
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[PANTS]
[SOFTLY] Captain, you okay?
-Yeah, I am.
-Are you okay, Captain?
Oh, yeah.
No, it looks worse than it is.
I think it was just a ricochet
or something.
MARIA: Oh.
Hopefully,
this is a better layover
than the last one.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[BOTH SIGH]
[CHUCKLES]
All right, guys.
-It's been an honor.
-BRODIE: Yeah.
Good job, Dele.
Just give me a moment.
Hey.
Are you gonna
go to the hospital?
I will.
-Okay.
-[GROANS SOFTLY]
BRODIE: Hey.
[BREATHES HEAVILY]
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
[SNIFFLES]
[BREATHES HEAVILY]
[EXHALES]
[SIGHS]
[GRUNTS SOFTLY]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[SNIFFLES]
[BREATH SHUDDERING]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[SNIFFLES]
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[GROANS SOFTLY, SIGHS]
Hey, it's me.
I'm coming home.
Yeah.
Yeah, you were right.
I'm gonna be a bit late.